[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339662", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty's monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f6", "question": "What Beatles song begins with the opening fanfare from the French national anthem?", "answer": "All You Need is Love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a265", "question": "Who established Paisley Park as his own record label?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6ec7a9e54d890926f6ca", "question": "What city is home to the tallest skyscraper in the world?", "answer": "Dubai, UAE -- The Burj Khalifa soars over Dubai at a height of 2,717 ft.  It has 163 floors with a hotel, residences and offices.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19e", "question": "What year did the construction of the Berlin Wall start?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b7b1e662d71a53651016", "question": "Who painted \"Madonna of the Rosary\", in which St. Dominic has been given a rosary by \"the Virgin\"?", "answer": "Caravaggio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd54fec223966ae8f88cf", "question": "What TV show won the most Emmys in 2018?", "answer": "The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e6a906d333868d34d734", "question": "Why did President Theodore Roosevelt ban Christmas trees from the White House?", "answer": "Because tree harvesting was depleting the country's forrests", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e37", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Up the Mountain to Alm-Uncle\"?", "answer": "Heidi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c2", "question": "Which two US states begin with the letter \"V\"?", "answer": "Vermont and Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e9", "question": "What Apache chief rode in Teddy Roosevelt's inaugural parade in 1905?", "answer": "Geronimo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b366", "question": "What nationality was the explorer Vitus Bering?", "answer": "Danish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fb", "question": "What sport features strikers and sweepers?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cb24877e98cb97778a15", "question": "Which European country was occupied by Britain from 1814 until 1964?", "answer": "Malta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339298", "question": "Which film sported the tag-line \"Just when you thought it was safe to go back in the water\"?", "answer": "Jaws 2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98b", "question": "What is added to Gin to make Pink Gin?", "answer": "Angostura Bitters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b7f6364247bf200fb879", "question": "Which Russian chemist created the modern periodic table?", "answer": "Dmitri Mendeleev", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19d", "question": "What Palestinian Terrorist group infiltrated the 1972 Munich Olympics?", "answer": "Black September", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8a", "question": "Who played the title role in the late 1990\u2019s sitcom \"Suddenly Susan\"?", "answer": "Brooke Shields", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdcfaec223966ae8f88fb", "question": "In the film \"Goodfellas\", what airline is robbed?", "answer": "Lufthansa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f34", "question": "What event is the subject of John Reed's book \"Ten Days That Shook the World\"?", "answer": "The Russian Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a569", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Keystone State\"?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339217", "question": "What Stealers Wheel hit is heard in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Stuck in the Middle with You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f4", "question": "What do you have if you are suffering from circadian dysrhythmia?", "answer": "Jet lag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d0", "question": "What were the surnames of Bonnie and Clyde?", "answer": "Parker and Barrow", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ebc", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Solla Sollew\"?", "answer": "Seussical", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a354", "question": "What is the only US state that borders a Canadian territory?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad6", "question": "In which continent would you find the Lena River?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eaf1cf83302ff91e46490", "question": "What city was nicknamed \"The Paris of the West\"?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe735e8eec85e375820b255", "question": "What did John Wilkes Booth trip on as he jumped on the stage of Ford's Theater?", "answer": "Bunting", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb735e75e259d786908732a", "question": "What two men are considered the most notable two-time recepients of Congressional Medals of Honor?", "answer": "Smedley Butler and Dan Daly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb5b525dad637d903c8819", "question": "In what city will you find Le Bourget Airport?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf2", "question": "In grammar, a complete sentence must include a predicate and a what?", "answer": "Subject", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a2", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the formulator of the periodic table?", "answer": "Mendelevium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b68e01dd7bf43be5e7de", "question": "What was the first Hot Wheels car?", "answer": "Camaro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3818ff048f679a45ab21", "question": "What is a unit that measures force?", "answer": "Newtons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab90", "question": "What was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer Empire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfe", "question": "In which movie did Kim Novak portray a witch?", "answer": "Bell, Book and Candle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a79c", "question": "Wellington is the capital of what island nation?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59029e41cad1ec93f27df755", "question": "What year was Strongbow cider introduced to the market?", "answer": "1962", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a160", "question": "When did Sid Vicious join the Sex Pistols?", "answer": "1977", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d6", "question": "Who danced alongside Shirley Temple in the motion picture \"Captain January\"?", "answer": "Buddy Ebsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ed43eccd244b1771b64500f", "question": "When a horse gallops its hooves act as almost four additional what? ", "answer": "Hearts", "category": "Science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396af", "question": "What actor founded the Purple Rose Theater Company in Michigan?", "answer": "Jeff Daniels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f17", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Ray Liotta and D. B. Sweeney?", "answer": "\"Shoeless Joe\" Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e95527ccba3ffe45786de", "question": "Malagasy is the native language of which country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeaa", "question": "Which German Nazi was known as the butcher of Lyon?", "answer": "Klaus Barbie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a34a12f2a7826b9b8724", "question": "What was E.T.'s favorite candy?", "answer": "Recee's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a550", "question": "Monterey Bay is located in what body of water?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe377bb0ada16518afdc04b", "question": "After giving up mural painting, Gustav Klimt designed for what industry?", "answer": "Fashion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22f", "question": "Which cartoon character has a girlfriend named Petunia?", "answer": "Porky Pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d5", "question": "Which series of novels refer to its main character as \"The Last Gunslinger\"?", "answer": "The Dark Tower", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c903", "question": "What is an emasculated stallion called?", "answer": "Gelding", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe1332be39efa6330e0fedb", "question": "Which is the driest, non-polar desert on Earth?", "answer": "Atacama Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff20e6631a458464a93c421", "question": "First published in 1842, \"The Masque of the Red Death\" is a short story by which American writer?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d3", "question": "What is the Latin name for the atmospheric glow also called the \"southern lights\"?", "answer": "Aurora australis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc5", "question": "In which European city are the headquarters of OPEC?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51ce3ff04d658268c931e", "question": "Who invented the rubber band?", "answer": "In 1845, Stephen Perry, of the rubber manufacturing company Messers Perry and Co., invented the rubber band.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc1e46ce05a3942286f17", "question": "Who originally recorded the song \"Blue Bayou\"?", "answer": "Roy Orbison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338feb", "question": "What kind of animal is Beatrix Potters' \"Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle\"?", "answer": "Hedgehog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a629", "question": "What U.S. state capital city is located at the southern shores of Lake Oahe?", "answer": "Pierre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bbc922560f0007efaba0e58", "question": "What is the capital of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b32354fbf195a31e15d73ad", "question": "Which American comedian was born Benjamin Kubelsky?", "answer": "Jack Benny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a903", "question": "What major river runs through the city of London?", "answer": "Thames", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be67", "question": "What faddish word comes from the Japanese for \"single number\"?", "answer": "Sudoku", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b74a", "question": "What kind of patterns are Dutchman's puzzle, log cabin and Irish chain?", "answer": "Quilts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2587231a458464a93c466", "question": "Which type of pastry is traditionally boiled before it is baked?", "answer": "Bagel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa1", "question": "What is the fear of the color purple called?", "answer": "Porphyrophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c86", "question": "Whose song \"Clubland\" begins his 1981 album \"Trust\"?", "answer": "Elvis Costello's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76712eec85e375820b28f", "question": "Into which body of water does the Yukon River discharge?", "answer": "Bering Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fce", "question": "Where did Aristotle believe the seat of intelligence was?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a25720565ad31a57c7ab", "question": "Which brewery won the \"top beer award\" at Chicago's World Fair in 1893?", "answer": "Pabst Brewing Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d4", "question": "What TV character's first spoken words were \"Goodbye kids\"?", "answer": "Clarabell the Clown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339843", "question": "Who directed the film \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89a", "question": "In the card game Blackjack, what two values does the Ace have?", "answer": "1 and 11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f22dff048f679a45aab6", "question": "What are sterile female honey bees called?", "answer": "Workers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339601", "question": "Where does Julia Roberts go shopping in the 1990 movie \"Pretty Woman\"?", "answer": "Rodeo Drive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd820a0d0de9af39e9d469f", "question": "As of 2020, how many vice presidents have gone on to become president in the US?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52b3d1bf59ab7d2e38102", "question": "How did Ben and Jerry learn to make ice cream?", "answer": "A correspondence course", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5e5e6ce05a3942286e32", "question": "Who won the 2009 Sporting News Major League Player of the Year award?", "answer": "Albert Pujols", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1c62baab681b092921a1", "question": "What car was the focus of the 2009 documentary, \"Love the Beast\"?", "answer": "Ford XB Falcon Hardtop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e5d", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Daffy Duck?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c48efbde8045e484669d", "question": "What is the name for a group of hyenas?", "answer": "A cackle or clan -- Hyenas are best known for the giggling, yipping sounds they make to express frustration and give warnings.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ff", "question": "Although it's referred to as a \"sea\", what body of water is actually the largest lake in the world?", "answer": "Caspian Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b614", "question": "First marketed in 1952, Pream was a brand of instant what?", "answer": "Creamer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b7", "question": "What 18 year old songstress did Kentwood, Louisiana, honor with her own museum in 2000?", "answer": "Britney Spears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975b", "question": "Who plays the last man on Earth in I Am Legend?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe768e8eec85e375820b2a9", "question": "What is the record snowfall in Phoenix, Arizona?", "answer": "One inch", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596761bf2b59efe0e9417ea4", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14066b0ee8c595b6d399c", "question": "Which 1920s play is the first major play written for children?", "answer": "\"Peter Pan\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8d", "question": "What violinist-bandleader was the first inductee into the Canadian Music Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Guy Lombardo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7c2dff048f679a45abf6", "question": "What was the first planet discovered by telescope?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b23", "question": "What make of car are the B\u00ad52's driving in the song \"Love Shack\"?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e98bcebfabb9c85d8a96e", "question": "Which former Archbishop of Canterbury was burned alive in 1556?", "answer": "Thomas Cranmer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb738325e259d786908732e", "question": "What book by George Orwell had a film adaption that was funded by the CIA?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e3f7525cb9e8bda682136f", "question": "The wreckage of which ship was discovered in 1985?", "answer": "Titanic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964e", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Mighty Joe Young\"?", "answer": "Gorilla", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a4", "question": "What were Wilma Flintstone and Betty Rubble's maiden names?", "answer": "Slaghoople and McBricker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d5", "question": "What US state name ends with three vowels?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6007849bbd51d85e222ab65c", "question": "What was the first fruit that was eaten on the moon?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8c7eec223966ae8f884b", "question": "What school did Viktor Krum go to?", "answer": "Durmstrang Institute", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddccb77980686f722d17a", "question": "What war saw the use of tanks in battle for first time?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a523", "question": "What is the capital of Lithuania?", "answer": "Vilnius", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d1", "question": "When not fighting crime, what did Underdog do for a living?", "answer": "Shoeshine boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0c0b469bb8041d07a04c", "question": "What is the official flower of Easter?", "answer": "White Lilly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5c", "question": "Alan L. Bean was famous as a what?", "answer": "An astronaut who landed on the moon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ba", "question": "What \"Twilight Zone\" writer also created \"The New People\" in 1969?", "answer": "Rod Serling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8db", "question": "Who won a record eight gold medals at the 2008 Summer Olympics in Beijing?", "answer": "Michael Phelps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4f", "question": "What year was Canadian author Margaret Atwood born in?", "answer": "1939", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067a6eff9c0647b50a8059", "question": "In 2016, which vessel became the first solar-powered aircraft to circumnavigate the Earth?", "answer": "Solar Impulse 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d0778e870e6f05ba600865", "question": "What is the capital city of Iran?", "answer": "Tehran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015f82dfe83fe1f2a824c29", "question": "When was Queen Elizabeth II born?", "answer": "She was born on April 21, 1926 at 2:40 A.M.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe73923eec85e375820b26c", "question": "What European capital used to be called Christiania?", "answer": "Oslo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121a4763c99d48cd169b02", "question": "According to myth, who rode the flying horse named Sleipnir?", "answer": "Sleipnir, known as the fastest horses, carried Odin the All-Father through the sky, over the seas, and across the lands.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c53f", "question": "How many feet in a fathom?", "answer": "Six", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f4", "question": "What was Maxwell Smart\u2019s agent number on \u201cGet Smart\u201d?", "answer": "86", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ee", "question": "What city provides the setting for \"The Phantom of the Opera\"?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971f", "question": "Which Australian played James Bond?", "answer": "George Lazenby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a533", "question": "The Missouri River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad18", "question": "Which female appeared on the 1999 US dollar coin?", "answer": "Susan B. Anthony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd8", "question": "In Arthurian legend, what was the name of King Arthur's magic sword?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339835", "question": "What instrument did Ray Charles play, despite being blind?", "answer": "Piano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ce", "question": "What TV spy often tried to pass himself off as a salesman for the Pontiac Greeting Card Company?", "answer": "Maxwell Smart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ede", "question": "What river provided the water for which Handel wrote \"Water Music\"?", "answer": "The Thames", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c587", "question": "What type of plant is a Saguaro?", "answer": "Cactus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e90", "question": "What was Fox's first series to win a TV season's Nielsen ratings?", "answer": "American Idol", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f1", "question": "What happens when you roll three consecutive doubles in a game of Monopoly?", "answer": "You go to jail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d75", "question": "Who was the first female comic to be called over to the couch by Johnny Carson?", "answer": "Ellen DeGeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339774", "question": "Which company created the Oscar-winning film Finding Nemo?", "answer": "Pixar Animation Studios", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76b58eec85e375820b2c1", "question": "Where can you hike the Bay of Fires?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac5", "question": "Lake Titicaca lies in which two countries?", "answer": "Bolivia and Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a578", "question": "Providence is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae30", "question": "The Gulf War occurred after Iraq invaded what country?", "answer": "Kuwait", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd9704323c87fd04dd15e47", "question": "Which US state was the first to officially recognize Christmas?", "answer": "Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc86", "question": "What color is the one-ball in a traditional billiards set?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a12f", "question": "At what address did the TV's \"Addams Family\" live?", "answer": "0001 Cemetery Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7beaa2b316f4693fb6791", "question": "The word \"squash\" comes from a Native American word meaning what?", "answer": "From the Narragansett word \"askutasquash\" which means \"eaten raw or uncooked\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae05", "question": "What did JFK call \"the most hazardous and dangerous and greatest adventure on which man has ever embarked\"?", "answer": "Putting a man on the moon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdab5a20b8cce1e6fda704e", "question": "An \"agelast\" is someone who never does what?", "answer": "Laughs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d71", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"From This World to That Which Is to Come\"?", "answer": "The Pilgrim's Progress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c760", "question": "What Greek physician is known as \"The Father of Medicine\"?", "answer": "Hippocrates", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd07", "question": "What hockey great wore the number 68 to commemorate the Prague Spring of 1968?", "answer": "Jaromir Jagr", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339630", "question": "Which TV show's theme song starts with the words \"Come and knock on my door...\"?", "answer": "Three's Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f0b4fe83fe1f2a824c12", "question": "At the Seder table, people eat and drink in a reclining position. What does this represent?", "answer": "Freedom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339415", "question": "The 1980s - 1990s sitcom \"Empty Nest\" was a spin-off from what TV show?", "answer": "The Golden Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b323204bf195a31e15d738b", "question": "Belmopan is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a522", "question": "How many neighbors does Lesotho have?", "answer": "Only 1", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c917", "question": "Hans Lippershey made the worlds first practical what?", "answer": "Telescope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d40", "question": "What two popular TV shows are based in the town of Hooterville?", "answer": "Green Acres and Petticoat Junction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc1b36ce05a3942286f13", "question": "In the \"Captain America: The Winter Soldier\" film, who was Winter Soldier?", "answer": "Bucky Barnes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f090ff048f679a45aa9f", "question": "Samhainophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c3680815febcc896f9268", "question": "What does the word \"Desert\" translate as from Latin?", "answer": "An abandoned place", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c190", "question": "Who was Joseph Merrick better known as?", "answer": "Elephant Man", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab974986faa38a764be528", "question": "What country did the Lada car brand originate from?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bc", "question": "What are the three main types of sugar?", "answer": "Glucose, fructose and sucrose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed5", "question": "In what year was Billy the Kid born?", "answer": "1859", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c334", "question": "What percentage of air is composed of nitrogen?", "answer": "78%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339115", "question": "Who wrote the 1896 novel \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea412bff048f679a45ab6d", "question": "What physical constant did Henry Cavendish first determine using two weights and a cantilever?", "answer": "Gravitational Constant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73405eec85e375820b22b", "question": "How old was the youngest American serviceman in World War II?", "answer": "12", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b4", "question": "What fruit is normally squeezed into a margarita?", "answer": "Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3a", "question": "Which basketball superstar had a major role in the 1996 movie \"Space Jam\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339320", "question": "What was the name of Bill and Ted's rock band in the movie \"Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure\"?", "answer": "Wild Stallions", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca23", "question": "How many constellations are used in modern astronomy?", "answer": "88", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa3c86ce05a3942286ea9", "question": "Which famous writer was San Francisco's first Black female streetcar conductor?", "answer": "Maya Angelou", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b420", "question": "Who was the first Chancellor of West Germany?", "answer": "Konrad Adenauer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b4d", "question": "In \"The Smurfs\", what was the name of Gargamel's cat?", "answer": "Azrael", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd3", "question": "What's the Western name for the image the Japanese describe as a rabbit pounding mochi rice cakes?", "answer": "The Man in the Moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f2", "question": "Metamorphic, sedimentary, and igneous are types of what?", "answer": "Rocks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339233", "question": "What band took on Will Champion as its drummer even though he didn't play drums at the time?", "answer": "Coldplay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c907", "question": "What is the main food of the Oystercatcher?", "answer": "Mussels", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59675e9d2b59efe0e9417e98", "question": "What two states are bordered by more states than any other?", "answer": "Tennessee and Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad5", "question": "What year did Andy Warhol die?", "answer": "1987", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339784", "question": "What saxophonist released the 1964 album \"A Love Supreme\"?", "answer": "John Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cb", "question": "What beer shares its name with the river that runs through Amsterdam?", "answer": "Amstel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c503", "question": "What actually is a shooting star?", "answer": "A meteor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9e", "question": "What food company produces the cereals Count Chocula, Franken Berry, and Boo Berry?", "answer": "General Mills", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b173", "question": "What year was construction of the Sistine Chapel completed in?", "answer": "1481", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9d", "question": "What does the \"touch of Midas\" turn everything into?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dbc", "question": "What holiday is celebrated with an aluminum pole, the Airing of Grievances, and Feats of Strength?", "answer": "Festivus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ea", "question": "In which Star Wars movie does Darth Vader reveal that he is Luke Skywalker's father?", "answer": "The Empire Strikes Back", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06a", "question": "Terry Nichols was the co-conspirator in what major crime during the 1990\u2019s?", "answer": "Oklahoma City Bombing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a237", "question": "What band released an album entitled \"Business as Usual\"?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971df4c89261e916c8e09a8", "question": "\"Groundnut\" is another name for what?", "answer": "The peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c88e5da22f44c2d77a29c3e", "question": "What narrow strip of water connects the Atlantic Ocean to the Mediterranean Sea?", "answer": "The Strait of Gibraltar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f2", "question": "What year did Volkswagen start production of the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b116", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db9", "question": "Whose death is a result of the souring of her relationship with her lover Count Vronsky?", "answer": "Anna Karenina's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c854", "question": "What nation is home to the Komodo dragon?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592ead77f83302ff91e4647c", "question": "What was a Portuguese moidore?", "answer": "A gold coin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a5be20565ad31a57c7d0", "question": "Who was France's first president and last emperor?", "answer": "Napoleon III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388fc", "question": "What fictional Harvard professor appears in Dan Brown novels including the \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Robert Langdon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26e", "question": "Architect Walter Gropius founded what famous German art school in Weimar in 1919?", "answer": "The Bauhaus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40c", "question": "What was Banlgadesh formerly known as until its independence?", "answer": "East Pakistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1df", "question": "In the restaurant world, what does \"Blue-plate special\" refer to?", "answer": "Low-priced specials that change daily", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3a", "question": "Thomas Jefferson is depicted on what US coin?", "answer": "5 cent coin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339913", "question": "What California city was the setting for the TV series \u201cEight is Enough\u201d?", "answer": "Sacramento", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e15", "question": "What's the name of the flat, square prison that holds the Kryptonian criminals in the Superman movies?", "answer": "The Phantom Zone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8a98a01dd7bf43be5e74f", "question": "How many bags of wool did \"Baa Baa Black Sheep\" have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ea", "question": "In which US state is Stone Mountain?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a415", "question": "What US city is home to the annual \"All-American Soap Box Derby\"?", "answer": "Akron, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90b", "question": "In 2009 what did the \"Sears Tower\" had its name changed to?", "answer": "Willis Tower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc1e76de0eb824d4052e3", "question": "What islands make up the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The British Virgin Islands is a former colony that includes the islands of Virgin Gorda, Tortola, Anegada, and Jost Van Dyke.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ecae22b790ded87bb38fd87", "question": "Who directed the seminal 1972 science-fiction film Solaris?", "answer": "Andrei Tarkovsky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339136", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek god Apollo?", "answer": "Apollo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a864", "question": "What is the literal translation of Montenegro's name?", "answer": "Black mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923c", "question": "What street do the women of \"Desperate Housewives\" live on?", "answer": "Wisteria Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c7", "question": "The Mus\u00e9e d'Orsay in Paris was originally what?", "answer": "Railway Station", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e48", "question": "What word do we derive from the Salish Indian word for \"wild man\"?", "answer": "Sasquatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600394ee57a0e35c43f8388f", "question": "In painting, what do you call the use of strong contrasts between light and dark?", "answer": "Chiaroscuro\u00a0is the dramatic effect of contrasting areas of light and dark in an artwork, particularly paintings.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc33eec223966ae8f887c", "question": "What actor won the inaugural Razzie Redeemer Award by going from a flop (Gigli) to hits (Argo and Gone Girl)?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c6", "question": "How many episodes of \"Growing Pains\" were made?", "answer": "166", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c136", "question": "How did UN Secretary General Dag Hammarskj\u00f6ld die in September, 1961?", "answer": "In a plane crash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339834", "question": "What movie won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 1991?", "answer": "Dances With Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ea5908d98002fdd633a1", "question": "What is the largest body of fresh water in the world by surface area?", "answer": "Lake Superior", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339029", "question": "Which very famous mystery novel was written by Gaston Leroux?", "answer": "The Phantom of the Opera\u00a0", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590681a8ff9c0647b50a8096", "question": "What is the name of Beyonce\u2019s sixth studio album, released in April 2016?", "answer": "Lemonade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba84", "question": "What early heavyweight boxing champion was nicknamed the \u201cManassa Mauler\u201d?", "answer": "Jack Dempsey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b6", "question": "How many sides does a trapezoid have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4de6206d333868d34d714", "question": "Who is known for running through the streets crying Eureka?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac8", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Montana?", "answer": "Helena", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacd", "question": "What does a heliologist study?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded12cea2747c8aff16d30", "question": "Who was kidnapped on the night of March 1, 1932?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11a", "question": "Along with Karl Marx, who wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\" in 1848?", "answer": "Frederich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a498", "question": "Into which sea does the Nile river flow?", "answer": "The Mediterranean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f95b1b655722f97b22684dd", "question": "What year did the Original Dungeons and Dragons box set by Gary Gygax and Dave Arneson debut?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa9220565ad31a57c81b", "question": "What was Hoover Dam's original name?", "answer": "Boulder Dam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d7522596a59cbdfbd3b4", "question": "Who gave the famous speech, \"Give me liberty or give me death\"?", "answer": "Patrick Henry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6b", "question": "What year did Brett Favre officially retire from his football career?", "answer": "2011", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f9", "question": "In which Shakespeare play does Antonio owe Shylock a pound of flesh?", "answer": "The Merchant of Venice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339081", "question": "Who wrote \"Born Free\", \"Living Free\" and \"Forever Free\"?", "answer": "Joy Adamson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3e", "question": "How many children did Rob and Laura Petrie have on \"The Dick Van Dyke Show\"?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea462cff048f679a45ab9f", "question": "Which fruit is also known as \"courgette\"?", "answer": "Zucchini", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339395", "question": "Which actor from the cast of the movie \"Rain Man\" won an Oscar?", "answer": "Dustin Hoffmann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede3666ce05a3942286dd2", "question": "What is the name of Charles Foster Kane\u2019s estate in \"Citizen Kane\"?", "answer": "Xanadu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e97197ccba3ffe45786f8", "question": "Melissophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Bees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5fa26ce05a3942286e45", "question": "Don Mclean's \"American Pie\" was dedicated to which singer?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c33d", "question": "How many furlongs to a mile?", "answer": "8", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3eafe38e4e5d4832e6317", "question": "Which company produced the World War II fighter plane \"Spitfire\"?", "answer": "Triumph", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3e5e44f0f6af5b06664b", "question": "In mathematics, which prefix refers to 10 to the power of 18?", "answer": "Exa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339423", "question": "What basketball player starred alongside Jean Claude Van Damme in the movie \"Double Team\"?", "answer": "Dennis Rodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c0", "question": "What \"island\", the southern-most tip of Brooklyn, has three miles of famous boardwalk?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597742ee284458f1d7854423", "question": "What \"America's Got Talent\" host replaced Nick Cannon?", "answer": "Tyra Banks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971e10289261e916c8e09b1", "question": "Which European city is the game \"Assassins Creed Unity\" set in?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339402", "question": "Which actor played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 movie \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b834fb6c85e9e634ff4d", "question": "Most common in British towns, what is the name of a street seller of fruits and vegetables?", "answer": "Costermonger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be4", "question": "Johnny Depp's breakthrough role was in which 1984 movie?", "answer": "A Nightmare on Elm Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c9", "question": "Until 1790, what was known as Jenkins Hill?", "answer": "Capitol Hill", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a421", "question": "What is the world's highest waterfall?", "answer": "Angel Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a813", "question": "The city of Liverpool, England is served by an airport named for what man?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b96", "question": "What was the first book Margaret Mitchell wrote?", "answer": "Gone With The Wind", "category": "arts"}]